Hey everyone once again welcome to D Script
Myself Gaurav and through today's video
we are going to understand
how you can draw polygons on any image that you have, that
means we have seen circles, we have
seen rectangles, we have seen lances,
but if we ever need to create polygons,
we have to create pentagons, hexagons or
something like that.  So let's see how we
can draw it, so basically the
polygon is visible, so like
I have created polygons on top of this image,
what have I done here, to cover up each side of it,
what have I done with it, I have used
polynom, so now
if you ever need to draw such polyns,
how can you do it through cv2 model, let's
see it here, so first let me
talk about the image, the image that we are going to take will
be this image, it will be for img 4,
here this image is inside img 4,
what will we do on this image, we will
draw our polygon, now for this I will take
you to a python file, this is
our piping one, where we are going to do all these reductions,
so for this I
will import the cb2 model here, so what I am doing here, I will
import it,
I am importing po and how to do the
cb2 model, the open cb model,
along with this we are going to import it here,
what will I name it, so
what will I do here, I will import the number
And let's run now the next thing that we will get is what
we have to do here
first of all we have to load our file
and what will we do on it we will
create our polymer so to load the file I am going to
create a variable here with the name of image as img
inside which I am going to use cbt you dot
here what will I do I am read which is the
function here to
read the file and what is the name of the file
here its name is four so I am
four so I am g un dot 4 you have the
name of the image and after that we
recise it this is a very big image
so all image equals you I am doing it here
cc you dot here we recise and recise
it using recise
so I said we are resizing the old image
and whatever size we want to make it here so I want
here this 500 * you have
images right now let's
see this old image once so to
see the old image what will I do here cv2 yes
You dot I will do that here I am going to do it for
you, for redefunction, it will be
read through the read function, for this first of all I have to
create a frame, so the name of the frame is s k,
after that next here is the image, I will have to
take it, so old image
dot here what will we do with the help of wait key, we will
close our windows, so
wait, I have given zero inside, then
after that I am doing it here, s c you
dot here destroy all windows, with which
we have to do
desktrod, run, ok, a
small mistake has happened here, I am
sir function will be installed here, from tomorrow we
will show here and inside that first of all
I have to name your stream, so I gave the name of
WS when I named the frame and
next I kept the old image here,
this is what you have, the
image is here, in this way it is showing a very good
image, now what will we do inside this,
whatever we want to draw our pentagon,
now if you want to draw, then
what will we have to do for that, now we will create a new image with the name,
so I will put
new underscore here  I am creating a bar with the name of IMG in
which I and you dot here
we have poly line, here the
function is yes what do you have, poly is your
line function with the help of which we are going to reduce it
now inside this polynom
we have many parameters
so I will write all these parameters here,
okay we will change these parameters one
by one and here I will remove this old image and
keep a new image, right
this is my new image, now inside this
first of all we have to give our image, so
I have given the image here, give the old image
next we get what is this
thing, first let's take care of it,
then after that we will proceed, so we
have this image here, inside this
our pits means that this
point which you are seeing, the coordinates of this point
means you have to give the coordinates of this point
inside the mobile,
then you have to give the coordinates of this point
inside x com a, you have to give the coordinates of this point inside x co a, you have to
give the
coordinates of the point inside x a
You have to give the coordinates of this point x A K. So, let's
talk about
how many ordinances we are going to give here. We are going to give punch
cards. Now what happens inside this is that the
pits that you have, the
pits that are formed inside this,
what do you have here, Napier is formed,
Nampal is formed, an array is formed.
What do you have to do inside this number,
first of all you have to make an array, you have to make
all completely fixed,
what do you have to do inside this, you have to
prepare a list. Now the
cards of all the five lists will be prepared like this.
Now this nampayryer is
totally with you, it will be face inside it like this.
You have to do this work in this
way, you will be able to prepare it here. Let's
write this formation
and finish the work quickly. So
for that, first of all I will prepare a list.
I have made this list. Now I have to
give the Nampai ones inside it. So let me do one thing.
I will bring the pits down
here because I have to give the number
here.  I will use the ARE function at NP dot here. I will use the
ARA function.
Inside this function, first we will
create a list and inside it we will
create a small list. Now I am
going to give any random point and
make a pentagon from it. After that, I will
show you here next how it will reduce.
Then we will keep adjusting it and it will keep reducing. So
first of all, the
image is quite big inside this image. Here you have this
image, right, this image is an image. So, we will
start from here. We will start from here. Then we will go
up. Then we will go down. Then we will come to this side. Then we will come to
this side. So, first we will
create anything random. After this, we will keep
adjusting. So, first of all, let us
give it here.
I have to go 120 within 120. 120 will become more. So, let us
reduce it by 100.
After 100, how much do you have? We have to
go 400 here. Okay, this has become our
first point. After that, the second point will be
above and will be on this side. So, we will go 100 with you
and it will be above.  So
what will happen to you, you are taking it near 300, here
this becomes your second point, your third
point will be somewhere here, your third point will be
somewhere here, that means the one you have for the
x axis in the a-axis will
run from here,
so it will change inside the x-axis,
so this 300 will easily remain 300, after remaining 300,
what will come to you next, I will
keep 400, right, this is our second
third point, now inside this,
a point will be created below here and a point should
also be created here, the
distance is from here, we will keep it
inside the a axis, we will go down inside the a axis,
what will we do with 400, let's give you 600,
right, a big box around 600 is
ready to be made here, now if we
come here on this side, then this
point is there, the points of this
point should be from here, so the
distance inside the x axis, I have to
keep it 100 only, the distance inside the a axis
600 right, I have it here.
Let's talk about this close.
This close means that if you have an image,
you close it because
we have one point here, one point here, one point here, one point here
and one point
here. Close means do you want to close it with the first point
or do not want to close it.
If you want to close it, you
can give it true. If we talk about color,
you can take the color you want
because the color here is in the
bag, so give it zero,
give 255 zero, I am giving it here. If we
talk about thickness,
how much should be its thickness, so I said a
thickness of 4 is correct here. If we
talk about line type, I am giving it in line type
16, that means your A type of
line, I am taking it
here date 16. Now if I do that here,
see it has become a polynom. Now it has
become a poly at a lower level. It will have to be taken to a higher level.
So I will take it up here,
okay, and take it up.  To go, I will
first have to delete this point. I have to make this
point 200. Okay, this 200 bike
angle has 200 points and it will be much smaller
here. Like where will this point go
and this point was just in front of it, this will also become 200
and it will become much smaller. It will become 500. It will be
much smaller. It will become 500. See, in
this way the pentagon has been formed. Now you
can decide according to yourself how to
make it. Now if I do not close it, if I make the close
false, the way
I did it here, here I pause,
close and run. So it is not closing.
Your lines keep joining all the lines. If you want to join
your
ending point, which is the starting point, then you
will close it. You will
not close it. I will start back here
so that I can close it, then it will
also be closed in front of you in this way. Now let's
talk about how many lines it has. Then you will
According to you, if you want to add text here, by using
point text, you can
also apply tax inside it, so I
think I hope you have understood
how you can make a polygon here,
I have told you to make a triangle,
you just have to make a rectangle here, if you want to
make any other polygon, then you
can make it easily, so that's all for today's
video, see you in
our next video where we are going to
discuss some more interesting topic,
until then stay with us, thank you,
good bye
[Prashaas]
[Music]